[{"question":"<p><strong>The locus of a point equidistant from the intersection of lines 3x - 7y + 7 = 0 and 4x - 6y + 1 = 0 is a<\/strong><\/p>","options":["line parallel to 7x+13y+8=0","circle","semicircle","bisector of the line 7x-13y+8=0"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The gradient of the straight line joining the points P(5,-7) and Q(-2,-3) is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/2","2\/5","4\/-7","-2\/3"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find dy\/dx if y=cos x<\/strong><\/p>","options":["sinx","-sinx","tanx","-tanx"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mean of seven numbers is 96. If an eighth number is added, the mean becomes 112. Find the eight number<\/strong><\/p>","options":["126","180","216","224"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mean of seven numbers is 96. If an eighth number is added, the mean becomes 112. Find the eight number<\/strong><\/p>","options":["126","180","216","224"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the median 2,3,7,3,4,5,8,9,9,4,5,3,4,2,4 and 5<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9","8","7","4"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the range of 4,9,6,3,2,8,10 and 11<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11","9","8","4"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the standard deviation of 2,3,8,10 and 12<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3.9","4.9","5.9","6.9"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Evaluate <sup>n+1<\/sup>C<sub>n-2<\/sub>&nbsp;if n=15<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3630","3360","1120","560"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a school, 180 students offer mathematics or physics or both. If 125 offer mathematics and 105 offer physics, how many students offer mathematics?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["75","80","55","125"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The cost of renovating a 5m square room is N500. What is the cost of renovating 10m square room?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N1000","N2,500","N2000","N10,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The cost of renovating a 5m square room is N500. What is the cost of renovating 10m square room?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N1000","N2,500","N2000","N10,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the rate of change of the total surface area S of a sphere with respect to its radius<\/strong><\/p>","options":["8\u03c0","16\u03c0","10\u03c0","14\u03c0"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Differentiate (cos&theta; +sin&theta;)<sup>2<\/sup> with respect to&nbsp;&theta;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2cos2\u03b8","2sin2\u03b8","-2cos2\u03b8","-2sin2\u03b8"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A binary operation * on the set of rational numbers is defined&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>x * y = (2x + x<sup>3<\/sup> - y<sup>3<\/sup>) \/ (x<sup>2<\/sup> + y<sup>2<\/sup>)&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>find -1*2<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11","-11","8","-8"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the range of values of x for which 7x&gt;3x+4<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x < 7\/4","x > 7\/4","7x < 4","-4x < 7"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate the standard deviation of the following data 7,8,9,10,11,12,13<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","4","10","11"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>If W is the mode and Z is the median of the following set of numbers 2.4,2.1,1.6,2.6,2.6,3.7,2.1 and 2.6 then (3W, 2Z) is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(2.6,2.5)","(7.8,5.0)","(2.1,2.5)","(6.2,5.0)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A trapezium has two parallel sides of length 6cm and 8cm. If the area is 42cm<sup>2<\/sup>, find the distance between the parallel sides<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6cm","8cm","7cm","5cm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The average of three numbers is 32<sub>5<\/sub>&nbsp;If the sum of the first two numbers is 131<sub>4<\/sub>&nbsp;find the third number in base 6<\/strong><\/p>","options":["43<sub>6<\/sub>","34<sub>6<\/sub>","23<sub>6<\/sub>","32<sub>6<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Three times the second term plus the seventh term of an A.P is equal to the twelfth term. Find the relationship between the first term and the common difference<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3a - 2d = 0","3a + 2d = 0","3a + d = 0","3a - d = 0"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>A fence of 36m is to be built to make three sides of a rectangular compound, the fourth side being a building. Find the possible lengths of the shorter side of the compound if the area enclosed is 160m<sup>2<\/sup><\/strong><\/p>","options":["20m,10m","16m,8m","20m,16m","10m,8m"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find dy\/dx if y = 2x<sup>2<\/sup> - sin2x<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4x+2cosx","4x-2cos2x","4x-4cos2x","4x+4cos2x"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>A bag contains 4x First Bank ATM cards (2x-1), UBA Bank ATM cards and 3(x+1) Zenith Bank ATM cards. If the probability of picking a First Bank ATM is 2\/5; how many UBA Bank ATM cards are in the bag?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","8","9","20"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Express the product of 0.000128 and 0.00125 in standard form&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.6x11<sup>-1<\/sup>","1.6x10<sup>-5<\/sup>","1.6x10<sup>-7<\/sup>","1.6x10<sup>-4<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>If(2x-1)+1\/(2x-1)=4, find the value of 4x-4x+1\/(2x-1)<sup>2<\/sup><\/strong><\/p>","options":["19","13","-13","-19"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>A student dropped an object from a building 100m high. If the height of the object above after t seconds is 100-4.9t<sup>2<\/sup>m. How fast is it falling 3 seconds after it is dropped?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["14.7m\/sec","85.3m\/sec","29.4m\/sec","70.6m\/sec"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>An investor who received N6500.00 as some simple interest rate collected a total amount of N7,800.00 after four years. How much simple interest would he have collected after two years if he had invested N9,000.000?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N1000.00","N10000.00","N650.00","N900.00"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>If the sum of the roots of the equation 2x<sup>2<\/sup> - 5px + 8 =0 is five times the product of the roots, find the value of P<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-8","1\/8","8","-1\/8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>If log<sub>10<\/sub>4=x, express log(12.5)<sup>3<\/sup> in terms of x&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4-3x","6x-2","4+3x","4(1-x)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the area of the region enclosed by the curve y = 2 - x<sup>2<\/sup> and the line y = -x<\/strong><\/p>","options":["<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","9","3","<sup>9<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Simplify (log(xy<sup>2<\/sup>) - 2log x + log y\/x<sup>2<\/sup>) \/ (log (y\/x)<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>For 0&lt;x&lt;y<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-3","3","-1\/3","1\/3"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Simplify (2x<sup>3<\/sup> - x<sup>2<\/sup> - 13x - 6 = 2x + 1) \/ 2x + 1<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(x-2)(x-3)","(x-2)(x+3)","(x+2)(x+3)","(x+2)(x-3)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The solution to the simultaneous equation 2x + y = 10 and 4x<sup>2<\/sup> - y<sup>2<\/sup>&nbsp;= 140 is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x=2, y= -6","x=2, y=6","x=6, y= -2","x=6, y=2"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the equation of the circle which passes through the points (0,0) and (-1,2) and whose center lies on the line y-2x+1=0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(x-1\/2)<sup>2<\/sup> + (y-2)<sup>2<\/sup> = 25\/4","(x+1\/2)<sup>2<\/sup> + (y+2)<sup>2<\/sup> = 25\/4","(x-2)<sup>2<\/sup> + (y+3\/2)<sup>2<\/sup> = 25\/4","(x+3\/2)<sup>2<\/sup> + (y+3\/2)<sup>2<\/sup> = 25\/4"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Evaluate lim<sub>x-&gt;1<\/sub> (x<sup>2<\/sup>+x-2) \/ (x-1)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0","3","2","1"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A student pumps a ball and its volume increases at the rate of n(16-t<sup>2<\/sup>)cm<sup>3<\/sup> per second. If the initial volume is (11n)cm<sup>3<\/sup>, find the volume of the ball after 3 seconds<\/strong><\/p>","options":["28n cm<sup>3<\/sup>","68n cm<sup>3<\/sup>","39n cm<sup>3<\/sup>","50n cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Score&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 0&nbsp; &nbsp;1&nbsp; 2&nbsp; 3&nbsp; 4&nbsp; &nbsp; 5<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>No. of students 24&nbsp; 8&nbsp; 4&nbsp; 6&nbsp; 10&nbsp; 8<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The distribution above shows the scores of 60 students in a class test. What percentage of the students scored at least 3<\/strong><\/p>","options":["60%","36%","66%","40%"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Subject Biology Chemistry Maths Physics<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Marks&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;95&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;2x+10&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; x&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 75<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>If the total mark obtained by a student is 300, what is the angle corresponding to the mark obtained in chemistry if the information is represented in a pie chart?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["120<sup>o<\/sup>","114<sup>o<\/sup>","48<sup>o<\/sup>","108<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A basket contains 5 MTN cards, 6 GLO cards, 3 9mobile cards and 3 Airtel cards. What is the probability that the card selected from the basket at random will be MTN or 9mobile cards?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3\/2","3\/4","1\/4","3\/5"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the difference between 1.867551 correct to four significant figures and 1.867551 correct to four decimal places<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5 x 10<sup>-3<\/sup>","4 x 10<sup>-4<\/sup>","5 x 10<sup>-4<\/sup>","10 x 10<sup>-3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In an examination, all the candidates offered at least one English and French. If 52% offered French and 65% offered English, what percentage offered French only?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["17%","35%","48%","45%"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the range of values of x satisfying the inequalities&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>2x - 5 &lt; 7 and 25 + 2x &gt; 15<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5<x<`-6","5<x<6","6<x<5","6<x<-5"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>If the 8th term of an AP is three times the second term and the sum of the first three terms is 18. Find the first term of the A.P<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4","2","3","8"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the sum to infinity of the series 4 + 3 + <sup>9<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub> + <sup>27<\/sup>\/<sub>16<\/sub> +...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["16","<sup>16<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>","1","8"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the equation of the line which passes through (-2,1) and is perpendicular to the line 4x - 2y + 1 = 0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2y - x - 4 = 0","2y + x = 0","2y - x = 0","y - 2y - 5 = 0"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>An interest covered a distance of 44cm before reaching a point Q. Calculate POQ<\/strong><\/p>","options":["63<sup>o<\/sup>","12<sup>o<\/sup>","13<sup>o<\/sup>","60<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first derivative of y = (2+3x)4 at x = -1 is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["12","-12","4","-4"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The minimum value of (x) = x<sup>2<\/sup>&nbsp;- 4x + 5 in the interval(-1, 1) is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","2","4","5"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>A company is to select three different handset phones from five different types of Nokia Brand and two different types of Samsung Brand. In how many ways can the company choose the handset, so as to include at least one Samsung brand?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["15","25","35","45"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"}]